You know, when people stand on the thing that you have said hurt you, there's nothing else to do.
There's nothing else to do because forgiveness begins at accountability.
It begins at being able to say like, you know what, even if you're like, that wasn't my intention, but I understand now.
I think that when we talk about actionable steps towards forgiveness, the first step is accountability.
And the reality is that you have to be listening.
So when we talk about how white people in this country be doing all this talking,
you can't even start to want forgiveness for how privilege has affected black folks.
When you keep doing so much goddamn talking, shut the f**k up and listen.
Stop trying to tell people their experiences are not what they are.
When your friends tell you, I experienced this, this is something I felt.
You can tell them that wasn't my intention.
Even if you say like, I feel like that may be something that you're applying because of this other experience.
You can have that type of engagement, but ultimately you have to start with listening.
If you want forgiveness, you have to start with listening.
And then taking accountability.